This is one of the most amazing animals on the face of the Earth.
هذا أحد أكثر الحيوانات المدهشة على وجه الأرض
This is a tapir.
هذا هو التابير (حيوان شبيه بالخنزير ).
Now this, this is a baby tapir,
والآن هذا حيوان التابير الصغير
the cutest animal offspring in the animal kingdom.
سلالة ألطف الحيوانات في مملكة الحيوان
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
By far.
حتى الآن
There is no competition here.
لا يوجد مقارنة هنا
I have dedicated the past 20 years of my life
لقد كرست العشرين عاما السابقة من حياتي
to the research and conservation of tapirs in Brazil,
للبحث والمحافظة على حيوانات التابير في البرازيل
and it has been absolutely amazing.
وكان ذلك رائعا قطعا
But at the moment, I've been thinking really, really hard
لكن في اللحظة الحالية أفكر بامعان شديد
about the impact of my work.
في تأثير عملي
I've been questioning myself about the real contributions I have made
أسال نفسي عن المساهمات الحقيقية التي قمت بها
for the conservation of these animals I love so much.
من أجل المحافظة على تلك الحيوانات التي أحبها
Am I being effective
هل أنا فعالة
in safeguarding their survival?
في حماية بقاءها ؟
Am I doing enough?
هل ما أقوم به كاف ؟
I guess the big question here is,
أعتقد أن السؤال الأكبر هنا هو
am I studying tapirs and contributing to their conservation,
هل أنا أدرس حيوانات التابير وأساهم في المحافظة على سلالتهم،
or am I just documenting their extinction?
أو فقط أوثق إنقراضهم ؟
The world is facing so many different conservation crises.
العالم يواجه العديد من الأزمات المتعلقة بالمحافظة
We all know that. It's all over the news every day.
نحن جميعا نعلم ذلك إنه في الأخبار اليومية
Tropical forests and other ecosystems are being destroyed,
الغابات الاستوائية ونظم بيئية أخرى يتم تدميرها باستمرار
climate change, so many species on the brink of extinction:
تغير المناخ ، العديد من السلالات على حافة الانقراض
tigers, lions, elephants, rhinos, tapirs.
نمور، أسود، فيلة، وحيد القرن، التابير
This is the lowland tapir, the tapir species I work with,
هذا هو التابير الذي يعيش في الأراضي المنخفضة نوع التابير الذي أعمل عليه
the largest terrestrial mammal of South America.
الثدييات البرية الأكبر في أمريكا الجنوبية
They're massive. They're powerful.
ضخمة وقوية للغاية
Adults can weigh up to 300 kilos.
البالغ منها يمكن أن يزن 300 كيلو
That's half the size of a horse.
هذا نصف وزن الحصان
They're gorgeous.
إنهم رائعين
Tapirs are mostly found in tropical forests such as the Amazon,
توجد معظم حيوانات التابير في الغابات الاستوائية مثل غابات الأمازون
and they absolutely need large patches of habitat
و قطعا هم يحتاجون لمساحات كبيرة من المستنقعات التي تمثل لهم موطنا
in order to find all the resources they need to reproduce and survive.
من أجل ايجاد الموارد التي يحتاجونها للتكاثر والبقاء على قيد الحياة.
But their habitat is being destroyed,
لكن موطنهم يتم تدميره،
and they have been hunted out of several parts of their geographic distribution.
ويتم اصطيادهم في العديد من المناطق التي تمثل التوزيع الجغرافي
And you see, this is very, very unfortunate
وكما ترون هذا شيء مؤسف للغاية
because tapirs are extremely important for the habitats where they are found.
لأن حيوانات التابير مهمة للغاية لصالح المستنقعات التي توجد بها
They're herbivores.
إنها آكلة للأعشاب
Fifty percent of their diet consists of fruit,
خمسون بالمائة من غذائها يتكون من الفاكهة
and when they eat the fruit, they swallow the seeds,
وعندما يأكلون الفاكهة فإنهم يبتلعون البذور
which they disperse throughout the habitat through their feces.
التي تقوم بنثرها في كل المستنقع من خلال برازها
They play this major role in shaping and maintaining
إنها تلعب الدور الرئيسي في التشكيل والمحافظة على
the structure and diversity of the forest,
بنية وتنوع الغابة،
and for that reason, tapirs are known as gardeners of the forest.
ولهذا السبب ،عرفت حيوانات التابير بأنها بستاني الغابة
Isn't that amazing?
أليس ذلك مدهشا ؟
If you think about it,
إذا فكرت في ذلك
the extinction of tapirs would seriously affect
انقراض حيوانات التابير سوف يؤثر بجدية على
biodiversity as a whole.
التنوع البيولوجي ككل
I started my tapir work in 1996, still very young, fresh out of college,
بدأت عملي في دراسة التابير في عام 1996 عندما كنت شابة وحديثة التخرج من الجامعة،
and it was a pioneer research and conservation program.
وكان بحثا رائدا وبرنامجا للمحافظة
At that point, we had nearly zero information about tapirs,
في ذلك الوقت كان لدينا تقريبا صفر من المعلومات عن حيوانات التابير
mostly because they're so difficult to study.
غالبا لأنه يصعب للغاية دراستها.
They're nocturnal, solitary, very elusive animals,
إنها حيوانات ليلية، منعزلة، ومراوغة للغاية،
and we got started getting very basic data about these animals.
و بدأنا في الحصول على معلومات أساسية عن هذه الحيوانات
But what is it that a conservationist does?
لكن ما هو عمل المحافظ ؟
Well, first, we need data.
حسنا، أولا نحتاج للبيانات.
We need field research.
نحتاج إلى بحث ميداني
We need those long-term datasets to support conservation action,
نحتاج إلى قاعدة بيانات على المدى الطويل للمساعدة في عملية الحفاظ على تلك الحيوانات
and I told you tapirs are very hard to study,
وقد قلت لكم إن حيوانات التابير تصعب دراستها للغاية،
so we have to rely on indirect methods to study them.
لذا يجب الإعتماد على طرق غير مباشرة لدراستها
We have to capture and anesthetize them
يجب علينا الإمساك بها وتخديرها
so that we can install GPS collars around their necks
حتى نستطيع وضع طوق للتتبع حول رقبتها
and follow their movements,
ونتابع تحركاتهم
which is a technique used by many other conservationists around the world.
وهي الطريقة التي تستخدم من قبل العديد من المحافظين حول العالم
And then we can gather information about how they use space,
ومن ثم نستطيع أن نجمع المعلومات عن كيفية استخدامهم للمساحة،
how they move through the landscape,
كيف يتحركون في الطبيعة،
what are their priority habitats,
ما هي مواطنهم الأساسية،
and so much more.
والكثير والكثير
Next, we must disseminate what we learn.
بعد ذلك مباشرة يجب علينا نشر ما تعلمناه.
We have to educate people about tapirs
يجب أن نعلم الناس عن حيوانات التابير
and how important these animals are.
وعن أهمية تلك الحيوانات.
And it's amazing how many people around the world
ومن المدهش أن العديد من الناس حول العالم
do not know what a tapir is.
لا يعرفون ما هو التابير.
In fact, many people think this is a tapir.
في الحقيقة يعتقد العديد من الناس أن هذا هو التابير
Let me tell you, this is not a tapir.
دعوني أخبركم هذا ليس حيوان التابير
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
This is a giant anteater.
هذا حيوان آكل النمل العملاق
Tapirs do not eat ants. Never. Ever.
لا يمكن أبدا أن تأكل حيوانات التابير النمل
And then next we have to provide training, capacity building.
ومن ثم علينا تاليا أن نوفر التدريب و نبني القدرات.
It is our responsibility to prepare the conservationists of the future.
إنها مسؤليتنا أن نجهز المحافظين من أجل المستقبل
We are losing several conservation battles,
إننا نخسر العديد من قضايا الدفاع عن تلك البيئة،
and we need more people doing what we do,
ونحتاج لمزيد من الناس لعمل ما نقوم بعمله
and they need the skills, and they need the passion to do that.
وهم يحتاجون المهارات والشغف لفعل ذلك
Ultimately, we conservationists,
وبالتالي، نحن المحافظون على البيئة
we must be able to apply our data,
يجب أن نكون قادرين على تقديم معلوماتنا،
to apply our accumulated knowledge
أن نقدم معرفتنا المتراكمة
to support actual conservation action.
أن نساند عمل الحفاظ على البيئة الفعلي.
Our first tapir program
برنامجنا الأول الخاص بحيوانات التابير
took place in the Atlantic Forest
كان في الغابة الأطلسية
in the eastern part of Brazil,
في الجزء الشرقي من البرازيل،
one of the most threatened biomes in the world.
واحدة من أكثر المناطق الإحيائية عرضة للتهديد.
The destruction of the Atlantic Forest
بدأ تدمير الغابة الاطلسية
began in the early 1500s,
في أوائل القرن الخامس عشر،
when the Portuguese first arrived in Brazil,
عندما وصل البرتغاليون أول مرة للبرازيل،
beginning European colonization in the eastern part of South America.
بدأ الاستعمار الأوروبي في الجزء الشرقي من أمريكا الجنوبية
This forest was almost completely cleared
تمت إزالة الغابة بالكامل تقريبا
for timber, agriculture, cattle ranching and the construction of cities,
من أجل الحصول على الأخشاب، الزراعة وتربية المواشي و بناء المدن،
and today only seven percent of the Atlantic forest
واليوم لم يتبقّى سوى
is still left standing.
سبعة بالمائة فقط من الغابة الأطلسية.
And tapirs are found in very, very small, isolated, disconnected populations.
وتوجد حيوانات التابير في مناطق صغيرة جدا منعزلة وغير متصلة
In the Atlantic Forest, we found out that tapirs move through open areas
في الغابة الأطلسية وجدنا أن حيوانات التابير تتحرك في المناطق المفتوحة
of pastureland and agriculture
من المراعي والمزارع
going from one patch of forest to patch of forest.
تتنقل من مكان إلى مكان في الغابة.
So our main approach in this region
لذا كان هدفنا الرئيسيّ في هذه المنطقة
was to use our tapir data to identify the potential places
هو استخدام المعلومات التي بحوزتنا عن التابير للتعرف على المناطق المحتملة
for the establishment of wildlife corridors
لأجل التعرف على ممرات الحياة البرية
in between those patches of forest,
فيما بين تلك البرك في الغابة،
reconnecting the habitat
إعادة ربط المواطن
so that tapirs and many other animals could cross the landscape safely.
لكي تستطيع حيوانات التابير وغيرها أن تعبر أرض الطبيعة بأمان.
After 12 years in the Atlantic Forest,
بعد 12 عاما في الغابات الأطلسية،
in 2008, we expanded our tapir conservation efforts to the Pantanal
في عام 2008، توسعنا في مجهودات الحفاظ على التابير لتشمل منطقة البنتانال
in the western part of Brazil
في الجزء الغربي من البرازيل
near the border with Bolivia and Paraguay.
قرب الحدود مع بوليفيا والباراجواي.
This is the largest continuous freshwater floodplain in the world,
إنه المكان الأكبر للمياه العذبة والفياضانات المستمرة في العالم،
an incredible place
موقع رائع
and one of the most important strongholds for lowland tapirs in South America.
وأحد أكثر المحميات أهمية لحيوانات التابير التي تعيش في الأراضي المنخفضة بأمريكا الجنوبية.
And working in the Pantanal has been extremely refreshing
والعمل في البانتانال كان منعشا لأقصى درجة
because we found large, healthy tapir populations in the area,
لأننا وجدنا تجمعات كبيرة من حيوانات التابير السليمة صحيا في هذه المنطقة
and we have been able to study tapirs
وكنا قادرين على دراسة التابير
in the most natural conditions we'll ever find,
في أفضل الظروف الطبيعية،
very much free of threats.
خالية من التهديدات.
In the Pantanal, besides the GPS collars, we are using another technique:
في البانتانال بجانب طوق التتبع ،استخدمنا طريقة أخرى:
camera traps.
الكاميرا الخفية.
This camera is equipped with a movement sensor
هذه الكاميرا مجهزة بحساس حركة
and it photographs animals when they walk in front of it.
وتصور الحيوانات عندما تمشي أمامها.
So thanks to these amazing devices,
لذا بفضل هذه الأدوات المدهشة،
we have been able to gather precious information
استطعنا أن نجمع معلومات ثمينة
about tapir reproduction and social organization
حول تناسل حيوانات التابير والتنظيم الاجتماعي
which are very important pieces of the puzzle
وهي أجزاء مهمة للغاية من اللغز
when you're trying to develop those conservation strategies.
عندما تحاول تطوير استراتيجيات الحفاظ على البيئة
And right now, 2015, we are expanding our work once again
وحاليا في 2015 نتوسع في عملنا مجددا
to the Brazilian Cerrado,
وصولا إلى سيرادو البرازيلية،
the open grasslands and shrub forests in the central part of Brazil.
المراعي المفتوحة والغابات الشجرية في وسط البرازيل
Today this region is the very epicenter of economic development in my country,
اليوم هذه المنطقة هي مركز التطور الاقتصادي في بلادي،
where natural habitat and wildlife populations
حيث يوجد تجمعات للمواطن الطبيعية للحياة البرية
are rapidly being eradicated by several different threats,
والتي يتم استئصالها بشكل واسع،
including once again cattle ranching,
والتي تتضمن مجددا مزارع تربية المواشي،
large sugarcane and soybean plantations,
وزراعات ضخمة من فول الصويا وقصب السكر
poaching, roadkill, just to name a few.
الصيد غير المشروع، قتل الحيوانات على الطرقات، فقط لذكر البعض منها.
And somehow, tapirs are still there,
وبشكل ما ظلت هناك حيوانات التابير،
which gives me a lot of hope.
والذي يعطيني مزيدا من الأمل.
But I have to say that starting this new program in the Cerrado
لكن علي القول إن بدأ هذا البرنامج الجديد في سيرادو
was a bit of a slap in the face.
كان كصفعة على الوجه.
When you drive around
عندما تقود السيارة
and you find dead tapirs along the highways
وتجد حيونات التابير ميتة على طول الطريق
and signs of tapirs wandering around in the middle of sugarcane plantations
وعلامات تجول تلك الحيوانات وسط زراعات القصب
where they shouldn't be,
أينما لا يجب أن تكون،
and you talk to kids and they tell you that they know how tapir meat tastes
وتُكلم الأطفال ويقولون لك بأنهم يعرفون مذاق لحم التابير
because their families poach and eat them,
لأن عائلاتهم تصطاده وتأكله،
it really breaks your heart.
هذا حقا يفطر قلبك.
The situation in the Cerrado made me realize --
الموقف في سيرادوا جعلني أدرك --
it gave me the sense of urgency.
أن هناك خطر ما.
I am swimming against the tide.
أنا أسبح عكس التيار.
It made me realize that despite two decades of hard work
جعلني أدرك أنه بالرغم من العمل لمدة عقدين من الزمن
trying to save these animals, we still have so much work to do
محاولة الحفاظ على الحيوانات لكن هناك الكثير بعد للقيام به
if we are to prevent them from disappearing.
في صورة أردنا منعهم من الاختفاء.
We have to find ways to solve all these problems.
علينا أن نجد طرقا لحل تلك المشكلات.
We really do, and you know what?
علينا حقا فعل ذلك و تعرف ماذا؟
We really came to a point in the conservation world
لقد وصلنا إلى نقطة في عالم الحفاظ على البيئة
where we have to think out of the box.
حيث علينا التفكير خارج الصندوق
We'll have to be a lot more creative than we are right now.
لنكن أكثر إبداعية مما نحن عليه الآن.
And I told you, roadkill is a big problem for tapirs in the Cerrado,
قلت لكم أن قتل حيوانات التابير على الطرقات في سيرادوا أمر خطير،
so we just came up with the idea of putting reflective stickers
لذا خطرت لنا فكرة وضع لصاقات عاكسة
on the GPS collars we put on the tapirs.
على طوق التتبع الموضوع حول رقبة التابير
These are the same stickers used on big trucks
إنها نفس اللاصقات المستخدمة في الشاحنات الكبيرة
to avoid collision.
لتجنب الإصطدام
Tapirs cross the highways after dark,
تعبر حيوانت التابير الطرق السريعة بعد حلول الظلام،
so the stickers will hopefully help drivers see this shining thing
لذا ربما تساعد اللاصقات السائقين على رؤية الضوء المشع
crossing the highway,
الذي يعبر الطريق،
and maybe they will slow down a little bit.
وربما يُخفضون سرعتهم.
For now, this is just a crazy idea.
حتى الآن إنها فكرة مجنونة.
We don't know. We'll see if it will reduce the amount of tapir roadkill.
لا نعلم ، لنر هل ستقلل من موت التابير على الطرق.
But the point is, maybe this is the kind of stuff that needs to be done.
لكن المغزى، ربما يكون هذا النوع من الأشياء التي يجب القيام بها.
And although I'm struggling with all these questions
وبالرغم من كل تلك الأسئلة
in my mind right now,
التي في رأسي حاليا،
I have a pact with tapirs.
عندي عهد مع التابير.
I know in my heart
أعرف في قلبي
that tapir conservation is my cause.
ان المحافظة على التابير هي رسالتي.
This is my passion.
هذا هو شغفي.
I am not alone.
لست وحدي.
I have this huge network of supporters behind me,
هناك الكثير ممن يدعمونني،
and there is no way I'm ever going to stop.
ومحال أن أتوقف أبدا.
I will continue doing this, most probably for the rest of my life.
سأستمر في القيام بذلك ربما لبقية حياتي.
And I'll keep doing this for Patrícia, my namesake,
سأظل أقوم بذلك من أجل باتريسيا، التي تحمل نفس اسمي،
one of the first tapirs we captured and monitored in the Atlantic Forest
أحد أول حيونات التابير التي مسكناها وراقبناها في الغابة الأطلسية
many, many years ago;
منذ سنوات عدة،
for Rita and her baby Vincent in the Pantanal.
من أجل ريتا وصغيرها فينسنت في البانتانال.
And I'll keep doing this for Ted, a baby tapir we captured
وسأظل أقوم بذلك لأجل تيد صغير التابير الذي مسكناه
in December last year also in the Pantanal.
في ديسمبر من العام الماضي أيضا في البانتانال.
And I will keep doing this
وسأأأستمر في القيام بذلك
for the hundreds of tapirs that I've had the pleasure to meet
من أجل المئات من التابير الذين سعدت بلقاءهم
over the years
على مر السنين
and the many others I know I will encounter in the future.
ولأولئك الذين سأقابلهم مستقبلا.
These animals deserve to be cared for.
هذه الحيوانات تستحق أن تعتني بها.
They need me. They need us.
إنهم يحتاجون لي. يحتاجون لنا.
And you know? We human beings deserve to live in a world
وكما تعلمون؟ نحن كبشر نستحق أن نعيش في عالم
where we can get out there and see and benefit from
حيث نستطيع أن نرى ونستفيد من
not only tapirs
ليس فقط التابير
but all the other beautiful species,
ولكن من كل السلالات الأخرى الجميلة،
now and in the future.
حاليا وفي المستقبل.
Thank you so much.
شكرا جزيلا لكم
(Applause)
(تصفيق)